happened to be with him growled so threateningly, that they accepted his
explanation without further questions.
Chapter 6
All that year the animals worked like slaves, but they were happy in their work. They
grudged no effort or sacrifice, well aware that everything that they did was
for the benefit of themselves and those of their kind who would come after them,
and not for a pack of idle, thieving human beings.
Throughout the spring and summer, they worked a 60-hour week, and in August
Napoleon announced that there would be work on Sunday afternoons as well.
This work was strictly voluntary, but any animal who absented himself from
it would have his rations reduced by half.
Even so, it was found necessary to leave certain tasks undone.
The harvest was a little less successful than in the previous year, and two
fields, which should have been sown with roots in the early summer, were not sown
because the plowing had not been completed early enough.
It was possible to foresee that the coming winter would be a hard one.
The windmill presented unexpected difficulties.
There was a good quarry of limestone on the farm, and plenty of sand and cement
had been found in one of the outhouses, so that all the materials for building were at hand.
But the problem the animals could not at first solve was how to break up the
stone into pieces of suitable size.
There seemed no way of doing this except with picks and crowbars, which no animal
could use because no animal could stand on his hind legs.
Only after weeks of vain effort did the right idea occur to somebody.
Namely, to utilize the force of gravity.
Huge boulders, far too big to be used as they were, were lying all over the bed
of the quarry.
The animals lashed ropes round these, and then, all together, cows, horses,
sheep, any animal that could lay hold of the rope, even the pigs sometimes joined
in at critical moments.
They dragged them with desperate slowness up the slope to the top of the
quarry, where they were toppled over the edge to shatter to pieces below.
Transporting the stone, when it was once broken, was comparatively simple.
The horses carried it off in cartloads, the sheep dragged single blocks,
even Muriel and Benjamin yoked themselves into an old governess cart and did their share.
By late summer, a sufficient store of stone had accumulated, and then the building began
under the superintendence of the pigs.
But it was a slow, laborious process.
Frequently, it took a whole day of exhausting effort to drag a single
boulder to the top of the quarry, and sometimes, when it was pushed over
the edge, it failed to break.
Nothing could have been achieved without Boxer, whose strength seemed equal to
that of all the rest of the animals put together.
When the boulder began to slip and the animals cried out in despair at finding
themselves dragged down the hill, it was always Boxer who strained himself
against the rope and brought the boulder to a stop.
To see him toiling up the slope inch by inch, his breath coming fast, the tips
of his hooves clawing at the ground, and his great sides matted with sweat,
filled everyone with admiration.
Clover warned him sometimes to be careful not to overstrain himself,
but Boxer would never listen to her.
His two slogans, >> I will work harder and Napoleon is always right,
>> seemed to him a sufficient answer to all problems.
He had made arrangements with the cockerel to call him three-quarters of
an hour earlier in the mornings instead of half an hour,
and in his spare moments, of which there were not many nowadays,
he would go alone to the quarry, collect a load of broken stone, and drag it down
to the site of the windmill unassisted.
The animals were not badly off throughout that summer in spite of the hardness of their work.
If they had no more food than they had had in Jones's day,
at least they did not have less.
The advantage of only having to feed themselves and not having to support
five extravagant human beings as well was so great that it would have taken a
lot of failures to outweigh it.
And in many ways, the animal method of doing things was more efficient and saved labor.
Such jobs as weeding, for instance, could be done with a thoroughness
impossible to human beings.
And again, since no animal now stole, it was unnecessary to fence off pasture
from arable land, which saved a lot of labor on the upkeep of hedges and gates.
Nevertheless, as the summer wore on, various unforeseen shortages began to make themselves felt.
There was need of paraffin oil, nails, string, dog biscuits, and iron for the
horses' shoes, none of which could be produced on the farm.
Later, there would also be need for seeds and artificial manures, besides
various tools, and finally, the machinery for the windmill.
How these were to be procured, no one was able to imagine.
One Sunday morning, when the animals assembled to receive their orders,
Napoleon announced that he had decided upon a new policy.
From now onwards, Animal Farm would engage in trade with the neighboring farms.
Not, of course, for any commercial purpose, but simply in order to obtain
certain materials which were urgently necessary.
"The needs of the windmill must override everything else," he said.
He was therefore making arrangements to sell a stack of hay and part of the
current year's wheat crop, and later on, if more money were needed, it would have
to be made up by the sale of eggs, for which there was always a market in Willingdon.
"The hens," said Napoleon, "should welcome this sacrifice as their own
special contribution towards the building of the windmill."
Once again, the animals were conscious of a vague uneasiness.
Never to have any dealings with human beings, never to engage in trade, never
to make use of money.
Had not these been among the earliest resolutions passed at that first
triumphant meeting after Jones was expelled.
All the animals remembered passing such resolutions, or at least they thought
that they remembered it.
The four young pigs who had protested when Napoleon abolished the meetings
raised their voices timidly, but they were promptly silenced by a
tremendous growling from the dogs.
Then, as usual, the sheep broke into >> Four legs good, two legs bad.
>> And the momentary awkwardness was smoothed over.
Finally, Napoleon raised his trotter for silence and announced that he had
already made all the arrangements.
There would be no need for any of the animals to come in contact with human
beings, which would clearly be most undesirable.
He intended to take the whole burden upon his own shoulders.
A Mr. Whymper, a solicitor living in Willingdon, had agreed to act as
intermediary between Animal Farm and the outside world, and would visit the farm
every Monday morning to receive his instructions.
Napoleon ended his speech with his usual cry of